# JAYANT KAUSHIK

Full Stack Developer

+91 9933006373

https://en.gravatar.com/jayantdps

Bangalore



With about 7 years of experience in development and extensive work experience in the layout building, design, and coding of websites, specifically in PHP, React and Python, I am a crucial Marketing hand with knowledge and understanding of databases, networking, web applications, and scripts development using various programming languages.

# **WORK EXPERIENCES**

**Software Engineer** 

IBM India Private Limited | 2016 -Present

**Server Administrator** 

Wipro Technologies | 2015 - 2016

## **PROJECTS**

## **Commerce Globalization**

Commerce Management Centre, OpenOffice and Jira

A CMS project for IBM Marketplace for uploading of product in different languages for different locations.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Coding UI pages for content updates.
- Translation of the given file to specific language using IBMs Content Management Centre and uploading the marketplace.
- Automated the final files to Jira.

### **Product Transformation Centre**

WordPress, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, HTML, CSS

Developed an IBM Consulting website where the admins can change the content dynamically, send newsletter and track user activities and users. A complete wordpress CMS made for IBM Consulting.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Coding of the UI pages for a dynamic website which can be updated using WordPress admin.
- Setting up Git-Hub repository for the project
- Coding of new WordPress plugins to meet business requirements.
- Integrating the website to IBM SSO using w3 authentication.
- Subscribe and Unsubscribe feature integration for users.
- Setting up mail server for newsletters and updates.

## IBM Service Platform with Watson

Angular,HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Carbon Design System, jQuery, Bootlint

Developed an open, standards based, and integrated platform, providing a next generation of easily consumed cognitive infrastructure services. The platform is built on IBM's Data and Cloud architecture and supports the entire managed services lifecycle, from designing to building, integrating and running services, with autonomic operations and augumented intelligence.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Coding of the UI pages
- Adding responsiveness and adaptiveness to the existing pages and creating the new pages.
- Setting up the Git repository for the project.
- Checking and modifying the Bootlint errors before production
- Using Chrome Dev tools to check CSS of the page and removed the unused CSS

#### Bluelines

WordPress, PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS

Developed a directory of IBM Consulting users segmented by their practices and organizational hirarchy by geographical locations.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Coding of the UI pages for a dynamic website which can be updated using WordPress admin.
- Coding of new WordPress plugins to meet business requirements.

## SKILLS

#### Technical

JavaScript/Angular/React

Python/PHP

Node.js

GraphQL

PostgreSQL/MySQL/MongoDB

Wagtail

Adobe Target

Optimizely

Photoshop

#### Professional

Effective communication

Team player

Strong problem solver

Good time management

# EDUCATION

B.Tech in Information Technology NITMAS, Kolkata 2011 - 2015

High School Baldwin Academy, Patna 2011

Senior Secondary Delhi Public School, Patna 2009

# ACHIEVEMENTS

Mentorship IBM Mentor (2021)

Inter House QUIZ 1st Prize, Inter House Quiz Competition.

Patna District Chess Rank 12, Patna District Chess Tournament

# INTERESTS

Cha

- Integrating the website to IBM SSO using w3 authentication.
- Setting up hot-jar plug-in for the website to track user activity and monitor using hot-jar account.

## **Digital Optimization and Localization**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Optimizely(tool), Adobe Target, GOOGLE Analytics Online Gaming

Cvclina

I was responsible for rebranding the product pages for IBM Cloud, and other Business Units such as GBS/GTS, as a single point of contact for the worldwide team including development in a/b testing and personalization of pages. This project also gave me the opportunity to work with the marketing team and develop their design and ideas live using my skills for IBM websites. The scope included optimization of IBM pages in terms of design, load time, and development of functionalities such as video leadspaces, iframes, anchors, widgets, and many more. Earlier jQuery was not a part of the development in Optimizely, and widgets were not created. As sole developer of this project, it gave me an opportunity to introduce Innovation and I added iQuery which helped in the creation of new functionalities with less code and seamless transitions. This also helped in improving UI experience and the introduction of more dynamic coding with the help of JavaScript. Then it led to Afterburner Program where as a power user for testing and personalization team, I completed the Adobe Target Training with assessment and got certified for the Adobe Target Fundamentals. This was then used for A/B testing and personalization experiments for designing complex experiments within the scheduled time. My prompt responses helped the team at the Centre of Excellence for testing and personalization to push tests live on time improving results.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Reviving the pages for IBM.COM and all the products for IBM marketplace.
- A/B testing of the created pages using Optimizely tool.
- A/B testing of the created pages using Adobe Target tool.
- This project revolved around the IBM pages optimization in terms of design, load time, and development of functionalities such as video leadspaces, iframes, anchors, widgets, and many more.

## Service Request Tool

Angular 8, Carbon Design System, Bootstrap, Nodejs

It was a project where I worked as a global developer to create an application for hiring process and travel process with IBM for IBMers. A large-scale project with a huge usage and exposure. A complete end-to-end application for management to use for resource hiring and requests related to travel and travel details.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Coding of the pages in angular to meet business requirements.
- Integrating the website to IBM SSO using w3 authentication.
- Take care of design change if any and also provide justification to it.
- Attend client calls to make sure the overall functionality of the application with approvals and workflow algorithm.

#### **Conversation Design**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Optimizely(tool), Adobe Target, **GOOGLE Analytics** 

Helped the team develop various versions of the mock designs of pages provided by them to go live. It also includes development where I needed to replicate the NorthStar on a different version of the page. Worked with Product Team to redesign and rebuild the IBM brand pages using different NorthStar templates adhering to the design. It helped them in getting more users to get involved with the IBM products and gave a seamless UI experience. This work also included campaigns that went live on LinkedIn and Twitter. My worked helped them in increased click-through rate, page visibility, and reduced bounce rate on important IBM pages. I Also fixed bugs related to IBM templates in no time and this helped greatly in business continuation. My knowledge, skills and consultation helped the team to understand the nuances which in turn helped our stakeholders to design their testing plans.

## **Royalty Management Tool**

React, Python, Nodejs, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, Carbon Design System,

Developed a cognitive application made using the MCA framework which allows users to adapt and make child applications from the main application. Build on React as UI, uses Python as BE with Postgres as the DB. This powerful application not only caters to the need of the user but also can be custom modified by the user as per the growing requirements.

Roles and Responsibilities

- Coding of the pages in React to meet business requirements.
- Integrating the website to IBM SSO using w3 authentication.
- Added user based roles and access in the application
- Developed e-mail functionalities with the Sendgrid integration
- Resposible for CI/CD structure and hosting of the application on IBM cirrus.

https://github.com/jayantdps in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jayant-kaushik-ab706593/

